Hello everyone and welcome back to English
Pod. My name is Marco and my name is
Catherine. And today we're going to
be visiting one of my favorite places I
must say. Really? You're a big meat eater.
I am. I have to have meat every day so
that's why I usually go to the butcher.
Alright so vegetarians be warned today's
dialogue is all about eating meat and
where to go to get meat so as Marco said
that place is called the butchers.
So we're gonna be visiting the butcher and
we're gonna learn all the different
types of meat you can find there. Great so
we don't have any to preview but
before we get started just like to mention
that you're gonna hear a
lot of different kinds of words
and we'll be back in a minute
to talk about what they mean.
What can I get for you? I'd like half
pound of ground beef please. Good choice.
Our ground beef is extra lean if you
know what I mean. Could I also have half a
dozen pork chops and two pounds of
boneless chicken breast? No no no chicken
breasts at the moment but we have
some nice chicken thighs. No that won't do.
I'll take this smoked ham you have
here. Okay is there anything else? Is this
salami and baloney you have here? Yes
it's very fine meat made it myself. Sounds
good. Okay that's it. Wait we have table,
ribeye and so long sticks. They are very
fresh. Just came from the slaughterhouse.
No that's okay really I think that's all
for today. Okay that'll be $34.50.
All right we're back so this butcher was
kind of creepy in the beginning. Very
creepy in the beginning. I think that's
usually the conception that you have
of butchers because they always have a
knife and they're always covered in blood
but it's not human blood. Right like the
movie Sweeney Todd did you see that?
Yeah like Sweeney Todd. So but we actually
took a look at a lot of different types
of meat that the woman was ordering so
why don't we take a look at these now in
language takeaway. Language takeaway.
Okay so the first is a classic cut.
This is something that we had at my house
about once a week growing up it's
called a pork chop. Pork chop. So a pork
chop comes from the animal the pork or pig.
Yeah we actually don't say pork
to me any animal. Pork just means the
kind of meat that comes from a pig so big
difference there when we're talking
about food we say pork. Oh wow and what
about a pork chop so what exactly is that?
Chop is usually just on the bone
and oftentimes it's fried. More baked
I guess but it's just a piece of pork on
the bone and a chop you just imagine a
knife chopping something. All right so a
pork chop very good and after pork
chops we were ordering some ground beef.
All right so ground beef is another
important one. Ground beef is beef that's
been chopped up and pushed through
a machine that kind of pushes it out in
very very small bits. Okay there's no bone.
So ground comes from the verb to
grind so to grind up meat to make it
very very small pieces. Right so if you
want to make a spaghetti bolognese
the kind of beef you use is ground beef or
even hamburgers. What are all right
exactly so ground beef you ground up beef
what other things would you grind? Oh
you could grind your teeth. Some people do
that when they're sleeping they grind
their teeth. You can grind you have pepper
grinders you know pepper sometimes
come in balls and you have to grind them to
make them smaller and broken down. Very
good so that's ground beef and from the
verb to grind. Now we are buying
some boneless chicken breasts. All right so
boneless as you have guessed means
without bones and chicken breasts are
usually just a really nice juicy kind of
tender cut of meat from the chicken
from the kind of underside of the
chicken where obviously yeah they have it
it's not a wing it's not a leg it's
just a chicken breast. All right so
boneless chicken but now usually it is
boneless right when you buy it at the
supermarket. Yeah yeah. Next up we've
got some classic deli counter favorite
these are our cold cuts. All right so
cold cuts now this means that they are
cold. Oh well yeah they're cold but I
think cold cuts the most important thing
to remember here is they're mostly
like kinds of salami or cured meats so
these are salt cured or they're dried meats
and you usually have them on sandwiches.
So like a salami sandwich. So like
cured meat you mean that meat
hasn't it hasn't been cooked. Oh no
it's not been cooked but it's treated in a
way that allows it to last for a very
long time. So they look like long long
tubes of meat. They look very dry. So they
look very dry like a jerky for example.
Alright so cured meat now for example
we have salami and baloney. baloney.
Now it's interesting because baloney is
actually spelled B-O-L-O-G-N-A so you say
baloney. Baloney or something like that.
Well I think it comes in the Italian
baloney. All right but it's definitely a
change that happened in the English
language when it came over from
Italy but baloney is a kind of meat that's
got a very funny-looking name. You
see you're more sophisticated than I am.
That's why you'd know this too.
I just speak Italian. All right so you have
salami baloney and pastrami. Pastrami
what about ham? Is that considered a
cold cone? You can have ham in the cold-cut
section because ham sometimes comes
in tubes that you slice but ham is also
just a normal kind of pork but ham is
cured you know. Like a smoked ham. Exactly.
A smoked turkey one of my favorite.
Very good and well now moving
on from the cold cuts we're gonna
concentrate on steaks. Ooh steak so
there are a thousand kinds of steaks in
this world and every city seems to have
its own kind but here we're only looking
at three the first of which is the tea
bone. All right the tea bone steak I think
is one of the most popular ones. Definitely.
It's a steak that's pretty big right?
Yeah well yeah I can be. And it has
a bone inside that looks like a tea.
All right so you're saying Marco that
the tea bone is named after the shape
and the look of this steak. Yeah a
tea bone steak. All right and as well as
our next one is also a rib eye. Okay so
the rib eye I think actually has a piece
of the rib in it so the rib is the bone
and there's a circle which is kind of a
it's the piece of meat is sliced off
the rib and the circle is actually part of
that rib so there's a little bit of
bone in it but it's not as bony as the
tea bone right. So it does have one
small bone that kind of looks like an eye
because you can see through it and
our next steak has no bone in the most
tender and the best steak you can
have cirloin steak. So I think the cirloin
is definitely the most expensive if
you're in a restaurant. Definitely the most
tender I think of all those delicious
and usually you can have like a big
cirloin steak like a half a kilo
like a 400 gram cirloin steak at a
friend who ate a full kilo. Really
a cirloin steak. Oh yeah. For is it a
competition or no there's a kind of
steak called the bistake alafirontina in
Italy it's the the Florentine beef
steak and it is it can be about a
kilo of meat. Wow yeah but you can't
even move after that. No you're you
fall asleep with your head and your
soup on the table. All right so that's all
the the meat related words that we have
for you today. So why don't we move on
now to fluency builder where we're
gonna take a look at some of the phrases in
this dialogue. Fluency builder. We're gonna
look at the phrases if you know what I
mean. If you know what I mean. Now I love
this phrase if you know what I mean. I do
know what you mean. Well it's I like it
too. So you can use it for sarcasm. Yeah
right or you can use it to kind of
insinuate something right? Exactly yeah so
here what you're saying you're saying
there's a double meaning in what I want to
say. So there's two things I could say
and I'm not gonna say it outright but you
know this thing that we can't really say.
So for example we can say she likes to
go out if you know what I mean. All
right so you're insinuating that not only
does she like to go out but maybe
maybe she goes out a lot a lot or maybe she
gets drunk or something like that. Yeah
so it's kind of like a double meaning but
you're trying to be subtle. Yeah but
it's not so subtle because you're actually
saying like this is not what I mean or she's
eating for two if you know what I mean.
Oh there we go. So you're
insinuating that well you're not really
insinuating you're telling me that.
She's pregnant. Eating for two is a common
idiom in English that means that a person
a woman has a well it's going to have a
baby. So here I'm saying hey do you know
this idiom? She's eating for two if you
know what I mean. So now why don't we
take a look at some other examples of how
we could use if you know what I mean
in different circumstances when you're
trying to insinuate something. Example one.
She's eating for two now if you know
what I mean. Example two. Tim had a
home run today if you know what I mean.
Example three. Jim and Laura are going
there separate ways if you know what I mean.
All right we're back so now that
that's clear why don't we move on to our
next phrase. So this one is accounting
phrase and for those of you who have heard
the word dozen before
it might not be so new
the phrase is half a
dozen. Half a dozen.
So that means half of twelve. So a dozen
is twelve and it's I'm not really sure
when this started being used in English
but a dozen is twelve and half a dozen is
then six. Now there's another phrase
or another saying that's very common a
dime a dozen. He's a dime a dozen. So
that means you can get twelve of the same
type of guys for ten cents. Right so
they're easy to find. They're easy to find.
Yeah. The dime a dozen. All right very
good and moving on to our last one.
When they were talking they said something
about the meat being lean. Extra lean.
Okay lean. This is not
mean lean on a door.
Right. This is not like
resting on something.
This is actually a kind of way to describe
food. And so food is lean if it's not
got much fat. It's not fatty. Okay
so if it's lean it doesn't have much fat.
Exactly. So I prefer to eat lean meats so
I often eat birds and poultry. So chicken
I like it pretty lean and if it's got
fat on it I'll cut the fat off. Okay like
the skin. The skin is fat right. Yeah.
All right so you can have lean beef.
It doesn't have much fat around it.
Yeah and in America actually on the the
packages at the supermarket it often
says the percentage of meat that you
have so it's ninety five percent lean or
ninety eight percent lean. So that means
you have three percent fat in there.
Exactly. My math skills are amazing.
All right. So now that we've finished with
all of these words I'm fluency builder.
Let's take a look at our
dialogue for the last time.
Hi. What can I get for you? I'd like half
pound of ground beef please. Good choice.
Our ground beef is extra lean if you
know what I mean. Could I also have
half a dozen pork chops and two pounds of
boneless chicken breast? No, no, no chicken
breasts at the moment. But we have
some nice chicken thighs. No that won't do.
I'll take this smoked ham you have here.
Okay is there anything else? Is this
salami and baloney you have here? Yes.
It's very fine meat. Made it myself. Sounds
good. Okay that's it. Wait we have table,
ribeye, and so long sticks. They are very
fresh. Just came from the slaughterhouse.
No, that's okay really. I think that's all
for today. Okay that'll be $34.50.
All right we're back. So Catherine, are
you a big beef or meat eater? Definitely
am. It helps that my partner and crime
is from Kansas City and they have the
best among the best sticks in
our entire country in Kansas City.
Wow I actually miss. There was back in
California we had the $6 burger from Carl's
Union. It was just basically beef,
bacon, cheese. It was just like this huge
burger with full of meat and obviously
a lot of calories. Oh yeah. But it was
delicious. I'm an egg or we are very used
to having some meat product every day
with our food. Yeah well it's the same
in the Midwest actually from where
we're from. It's the same in the
Midwest because people in the Midwest
generally think that if you're not eating
meat then you know what are you eating?
Bread. Right. Corn. So meat is considered
a healthy part of the day and you
definitely eat it with your meals.
Yeah and I'm sure our vegetarian listeners
might not appreciate this but you
know it's just kind of different diet.
Some people eat for example rice every day.
So we're in other countries you wouldn't
really have rice every day. Or for
example when I was in Chile had a lot of
potatoes. Really? A lot of potato. Have
you ever had an Argentine steak? I hear
they have the best beef in the world.
They are not only delicious but they are
very inexpensive and it's amazing.
You can have a complete steak buffet for
like I don't know like I can't even
remember but it was just I sat there for
three hours and couldn't move and come
to eating. Yeah was it is it true you can
eat it with a spoon? It's so soft. Some
of the meat is very very tender and not
if it's grilled you can't really do
that but in other preparations it's
almost like that. With a nice butter sauce.
Orbs. Alright so you can be hungry.
I know you've made me hungry. I think
we're gonna take off and have some burgers
in that. Alright so if you have any
questions, any comments please come to our
website at EnglishPod.com and we're
there to answer any doubts. And we'd love
to know what your favorite
foods are meat or otherwise so post
something on our website.
I'll see you there soon. Bye. Bye.